# **Career Goal & Objective**

Continue to learn and gain more experience from difference aspects. To excel in whatever work and challenges offered to me.

#### **Profile**

Strong experience background in problem-solving. Ensure objectives are completed on time, and successfully. Leadership in Supporting & achieving high-performance teams. Secure a promising position that offers both challenges and opportunities for growth. Willing to take up any challenges.

# **Academic Qualification**

2012 - 2013: Institute Of Maritime & Business Management (CERTIFICATE IN MARITIME STUDIES)

2011: Sterling Campus (IATA - CERTIFICATE IN DANGEROUS GOODS INITIAL 1,3 & 6)

1999 - 2003: Bendemeer Secondary School

GCE 'N' level certificate (with 4 credits)

GCE O level certificate (with 3 credits)

1993 - 1998: Bendemeer Primary School (PSLE certificate)

# **Knowledge, Skills & Abilities**

- Ability to work independently and unsupervised
- Knowledge & Operations in Sea-Freight arrangements/ Handling full Import & Export Shipments according to Shipper/ Consignee requirements. Terms such as CIF, FOB.
- Operations Knowledge in Total Logistics, Projects/ Break bulk & Odd Size Cargo shipments.
- Knowledge in Total Logistics, Supply & Cold Chain/ Warehousing & Yard Storage, Chemical Logistics Transportation.

## **Employment History**

**Company: Rejoice Container Services Pte Ltd** 

Job Title: Project Manager

Salary: S\$5,200

Package: Company Car provided with full reimburse

Date Joined: 1<sup>ST</sup> January 2015 - 31<sup>st</sup> December 2018

## Job Scope

1. Accountable for Existing & New Potential customer/ Business revenue to the overall profitability of the organisation. Handling of RFQ tender bidding for Projects, Presentations and offering suitable logistics services or solutions with directions and strategies.

- 2. Attending to site/ Conduct Cargo Survey & Road Routing with customers and advice on the appropriate handling methods & transportation required. Execute projects according to tender specifications within budget. Project monitoring and resolution of on- site issues, Ensure safety standards are met. Coordinate Civil Work between clients and subcontractors. Handle and administer orders resolve discrepancies with appointed contractors and vendors.
- 3. Pricing to meet project material specifications/ requirements, negotiate with contractors and suppliers to meet projects objectives in areas of delivery schedule and pricing. Involves Operations in projects Marine Offshore Oil & Gas such as heavy lift equipment and heavy haulage. Meetings to review and advise critical issues or improvements measures. Continuous follow up on project progress and status updates.
- 4. Gathering Marketing intelligence and build strong working relationship internally with operations team and externally so as to achieve high customer satisfaction leading to increase in sales revenue. Identify major potential customers for development Establish for long term logistics contracts.
- 5. Customers driven and cost effective Logistics Solutions to customers and ensure smooth and complete execution. Such as recommending the best method of delivery for a Break-bulk / Out of Gauge cargo using the most appropriate transportation or haulage means at the most efficient cost for the customers form Port to Door & End destination.
- 6. Business supports in supply chain services with 3<sup>rd</sup> Party Warehousing. (E.g. Storage & Distribution, Chemical Industry/ Logistics, Oil & Gas Sectors provision of Total Projects logistics solutions.

- Execute Projects according to tender specifications within budget in offering suitable logistics services or solutions in tandem with overall corporate directions and strategies.
- Operations Experience gain in Supply Chain 3PL & 4PL/ Chemical Logistics, Cold Chain, Marine Offshore/ ShipBuilding, Oil & Gas / Heavy Equipment Industry, Building & Construction, Break Bulk & Odd Size Cargo.
- Knowledge & Operations Skills gain in Total Logistics, Etc; Chemical Transportation into Jurong Island Discharging Plant, Supply Chain in 3PL & 4PL, Warehousing & Open Yard Storage, Heavy lifting equipment, Heavy Haulage in Handling Special Equipment During Transportation, Moving & Final Positioning of Machinery.
- Proven initiative and ability to work with minimal supervision.

Reasons for Leaving: Restructuring for my department as affected by the current down-turn economic for OOG & Projects Cargo.

#### #2

# Company: Transoceanic Projects & Development (Singapore) Pte Ltd

Job Title: Sales & Marketing Executive / Operations Executive

Salary: S\$4,800

Date Joined: 1<sup>ST</sup> January 2013 - 30<sup>th</sup> October 2014

### Job Scope

- 1. To provide functional assistance to Country Manager, Procurement in Sourcing, negotiating and procuring materials/equipment's required and services at the most competitive price, timely delivery and in accordance with projects requirements. To explore more alternative Supplier/Manufactures and Contractors who provide quality supply and services.
- 2. Following up closely and ensure timely receipt of quotations. Delivery and pricing to meet project material specifications/ requirements, Negotiate with contractors and suppliers to meet projects objectives in areas of delivery schedule and pricing.
- 3. Meetings to review and advise critical issues or improvements measures. Continuous follow up on project progress and status updates.
- 4. Gathering Marketing intelligence and build strong working relationship internally and externally so as to achieve high customer satisfaction leading to increase in sales revenue.
- 5. Identify major potential customers for development Establish Regional and Major Accounts for long term logistics contracts, Customers driven and cost effective Logistics Solutions to customers and ensure smooth and complete execution. Such as recommending the best method of delivery for a Break-bulk / Out of Gauge cargo using the most appropriate

- transportation or haulage means at the most efficient cost for the customers from start to end destination.
- 6. Assisting Country Manger with business deals in supply chain services (e.g. Warehouse Storage, provision of Total Projects logistics solutions). Selling of company's supply chain services on End to End delivery of Project/ Break Bulk cargo. Achieving the sales target revenue and profitability growth through developing new customers and service existing base and offering suitable logistics services solutions in tandem with overall corporate directions and strategies. Carries out ad-hoc duties as assigned by Management.

### **Experience Gained**

- Execute projects according to tender specifications within budget in offering suitable logistics services or solutions in tandem with overall corporate directions and strategies.
- Experience gain in Supply Chain/ Marine Offshore Oil & Gas / Mining and Heavy Equipment Industry, Building & Construction, Break bulk & Odd Size Cargo.
- Knowledge in Heavy lifting equipment, Heavy Haulage Transportation, Moving & Final Positioning of Machinery.
- Planning and set up Master Schedule for Projects and Resolve on site issues.
- Proven initiative and ability to work with minimal supervision.

Reasons for Leaving: Singapore Office Close Down.

Company: BULKHAUL (SINGAPORE) PTE LTD (1 Year Contract)

Job Title: Commercial Executive

Salary: S\$3,800

Date Joined: 1<sup>ST</sup> October 2011 - 20<sup>th</sup> July 2012

### Job Scope

- 1. Servicing of key account clients. Liaison with (shippers/overseas agents), shipping lines, operations team, co-ordination to be done with container depot on tanks cleaning, tank allocation. Daily orders/planning and deliveries to the local customers. Ensure that all datelines and requirements are met as per request by customers.
- 2. Tracking and monitor on Empty Re-Positioning of Containers from overseas office. Charges for tank hired Duration, abortive charges, damages claims and storage charges from PSA & depots.
- 3. Allocation the movement of ISO tanks & containers such as (SOC Containers). Empty returning of tanks. Liaison with hauliers for both loading and unloading of tanks, empty collections to be arrange from various ports & depot.
- 4. Sourcing and negotiates sea freight rates with shipping lines. Offers quotation on feeder rates for various ports to customers based on different destinations & Ports.
- 5. Liaison with customers on loading of products/chemicals. Checking & processing of documentation such as MSDS, DG Application to Liner, Tank cleanliness cert, BV cert and all shipping & declaration documentations. Handle custom declaration permit. Updating of incoming shipments and payment made to shipping line/ carriers.
- 6. Co-ordinate customer request with operation teams, follow-up on sales leads and routing instructions.

### **Experience Gained**

- Knowledge in ISO tanks/ SOC Containers movements and documents declaration such as (**Application on Dangerous Class Cargo**).
- Transportation of Hazardous and non-hazardous liquids/ Cargo.
- Knowledge gain in IMDG Code (International Maritime Dangerous Goods)
- Knowledge gain in Dangerous Class Cargo, (SOC & NVOCC).
- Good team player and Multitasking capabilities.
- Excellent organizational and motivational skills.

**Reason for Leaving:** Due to contract job wish to look for something permanent as to be able to have a better fulfilment in the jobs and commitment to the company.

Company: JNC Line (S) Pte Ltd

Job Title: Import/Customer Service

Salary: S\$2,800

Date Joined: 1st Feb 2011 - 30th Sep 2011

### Job Scope

- 1. Servicing of key account clients. Foster and maintain customer relationship. Arrange and Coordinate Import shipping matters according to customers' requirements. Plan warehouse activities and deliveries for the Local Customers. Ensure that all datelines are met.
- 2. Maintaining good relations with sales team, Handling attending and responding timely to customer's on freight inquires. Preparation of customs clearance permits via Tradenet. Action to be taken as per request from customers to the warehouse/ Operations teams.
- 3. Working closely Liaison with overseas partner's shippers & consignee /overseas agents/ various carriers/ co-loaders and vendors to support timely receipt and delivery of shipments.
- 4. Managing clients' account and stock reports. Providing Rates, Arranging of Transportation on the collection of cargo from consignee/ shippers premises.
- 5. Preparing customers invoice on the warehouse charges, documentation for individual shipments and arranging of payments to shipping line. Timely billing to customers on all completed jobs.
- 6. Co-ordinate customer Request with operation Teams, Follow-up on Sales Leads and routing instructions.

### **Experience Gained**

- Knowledge on Import and Export documentation ( FCL & LCL )
- Knowledge in world shipping trade & Tradenet Declaration (Free Trade Zone & Bonded Warehousing).
- Good team player and Multitasking capabilities.
- Proven initiative and ability to work with minimal supervision.
- Excellent organizational and motivational skills.

**Reason for Leaving:** In search of better career advancement.

**Notice Period: Immediate** 

Salary Expected: \$5,000.00 Negotiable